Mahesh Attarde Coder.mahesh@gmail.com +91-8790520855 | Github Dev.to

Summary

Self-motivated, adaptable, independent individual in software industry with proven records for solving complex problems and delivering results, capable of working with limited supervision, proactive in managing tasks and status

Quality Experience in building tools, flows, sdk in domains databases, compiler, cloud data center

Professional Experience

ML-HLS-FPGA Consultant | Remote | Jan 2022-Present

- Built CNN, DNN and K-means accelerator with FPGA with ML Compiler
- Accelerated delivery by 2 months with solution requiring understanding of architecture, design and programming lang of customer requirement and reduction of human efforts
- Exercised Product Development best practices to reach automobile customer approval

AMD-Xilinx | Senior Software Engineer | Dec 2016 - Nov 2022

- Built HLS LLVM developer tools, SDK framework and demo applications in Vitis
- Architected asynchronous event framework for fastest possible execution of workload
- Achieved speedup of more than 100% to team deliverables
- Achieved 92% of test suite bring up including unit test and apps for Patented Compiler
- Led Object Oriented model for Requirement Specification, designed & developed tool chain with end-to-end responsibilities in C++ and Python
- Sound Understanding of software development life cycles including Agile and Spiral
- Expertise in architectural patterns like multithreading, IPC, web services and design patterns from C++ Boost-STL, automation with python along with gdb debugging
- Good experience in managing tasks over local remote teams to deliver value

Progress Software | Software Engineer | March 2016 - Nov 2016

- Built SQL Engine feature, dynamic sample statistics based on lex-yacc, C/C++
- Worked on Legacy source built over 15 years, bug fixing and debugging for CDC
- Contributed to Hack-a-thon for multithreaded query plan, less to 2 times speedup

Blaize (Thinci) | Software Engineer | June 2014 - Feb 2016

- Built tools, OpenCL- OpenVx **SDK** framework for Computer vision HPC GPU hardware startup
- Lead frontend library support end-to-end using C++ in pipelined architecture
- Designed test-suites from scratch for all frontend library mock ups
- Delivered value to customer in deadline with pair programming which led to 100 times fast low cost DNN models for customer

Project Co-ordinator | May 2018

- SQL-Data frame accelerator with **LLVM JIT** in columnar database Implementation
- Achieved 6 times speedup on execution and ~ 2 time less data movement of data

Education

- Executive Alumnus, IIM Indore (2023)
- Certified Agile methodologist from Google.
- System Major, MTech in Computer Science and Engineering, IIIT Hyderabad. (2014)
- Distinction, Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering, Pune University. (2011)
 linkedin.com / Blog